Guide to the Men of Yale Series Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Men of Yale Series records
1872-1966
RU 929
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7
The records consist of lists, typescripts, correspondence, and financial records relating to the Men of Yale Series edited by Albert B. Crawford (Yale 1913).
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 49 (YRG 49), Papers and projects on Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of the President, 1974.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by volume number.
Biographical / Historical
The Men of Yale Series was conceived and financed by Edwin Foster Blair (Yale 1925, LLB 1928, and LLD). The series consisted of four published volumes (three volumes of Yale football men, 1872-1960 and one volume of Yale Phi Beta Kappa men, 1778-1959) and one unpublished volume on Yale honorary degree recipients. The series was published from 1962-1968.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of lists, typescripts, correspondence, and financial records relating to the Men of Yale Series edited by Albert B. Crawford (Yale 1913).
College athletes; Greek letter societies; Blair, Edwin Foster, 1901-; Crawford, Albert Beecher, 1891-; Phi Beta Kappa. Connecticut Alpha (Yale University); Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Football; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students
- Men of Yale Series records, Accession 1974-A-011
  - Football Yale Men 1872-1919: Vol 1, Financial lists of Yale Men (Box 1)
  - Football Yale Men 1920-1960: Vol 2, Financial lists of Yale Men (Box 2)
  - Football Yale Men 1920-1960: Vols 2 -3, Football Misc. (Box 3)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Yale Men 1778-1959: Vol 4, Correspondence -Financial -History of -General procedure for research (Box 4)
  - Lists of Members, 1872-1900 (Box 5)
  - Lists of Members, 1901-1920 (Box 6)
  - Lists of Members, 1921-1940 (Box 7)
  - Lists of Members, 1941-1949 (Box 8)
  - Lists of Members (scattered), 1778-1959 (Box 9)
  - Lists of Members (scattered). Also: computer print-out of lists of men, 1778-1959 (Box 10)
  - Typescript of Vol 5 -Honorary Degrees from Yale (Box 11)
  - Typescript of Vol 5 -Honorary Degrees from Yale (Box 12)
  - Typescript of Vol 5 -Honorary Degrees from Yale (Box 13)
  - Albert Beecher Crawford -personal -drafts and reprints of his articles, 1929-1966 (Box 14)
  - Typed Index cards (Box 15–17)